

■ +91 8138044748 | ■ ajithd78564@gmail.com | ■ github.com/mr-speedster | ■ linkedin.com/in/ajith-d-0194431b5/

Personal Profile

My name is Ajith D, and I am 21 years old. I have recently completed my Engineering degree (BTech) in Computer Science from the College of Engineering and Management Punnapra, which is under Kerala Technological University (KTU). Currently, I am an Associate Software Developer at SOTI. I am calm, hardworking, and responsible. One of my most appreciated qualities is dedication. Since I am from Kerala, my mother tongue is Malayalam, in which I am fluent. I also speak English. I am skilled in programming and development, and I have a keen interest in learning new things and keeping up with the latest technology.

Education

College of Engineering and Management

Alappuzha, Kerala

BTech in Computer Science and Engineering Punnapra

August 2019 - July 2023

- Computer Science Association Treasurer
- Peer to Peer learning community administrator
- Core Papers: Data Structures, Logic Design, Object Oriented Programming using Java, Graph Theory, Computer Organisation and Architecture, Database Management Systems, Operating System, FLAT, Computer Networks, Compiler Design, Computer Graphics and Image Processing, Algorithm Analysis and Design, Artificial Intelligence
- Elective Papers: Programming in Python, Cloud Computing, Programming Paradigms, Data Mining, Blockchain Technologies
- **CGPA:** 8.33 (First Class with Distinction)

NRPMHSS Kayamkulam

Kayamkulam, Kerala

July 2017 - Apr 2019

Specialised in Physics, Chemistry, and Maths with Computer Science

• Percentage: 82.75

NRPMHSS Kayamkulam Kayamkulam, Kerala

High School July 2012 - Apr 2017

• Percentage: 96.67

Projects

- **interV:** A system comprising a digital human and user management which has the ability to conduct interviews on specific company's patterns, analyze the interviewee's answers and mannerisms and provide an analyzed report on the same
- **Kitchen Management System:** a secure kitchen management system to prevent LPG gas leakage, the excessive fire that can cause explosions, wastage of water and also alert the user
- Website: A Website for College of Engineering and Management, Punnapra (https://cempunnapra.org/)
- **Data Visualization Software:** Collaborated with the CEO (SAKS Equipments Private Limited), Sandeep KS together with my three college colleagues to design Data Visualization Software in Chromatography Machines using C language.
- **CS-Buddy:** A project to manage department-wise data of students and faculties and can interact with students using Laravel and MySql database. (https://github.com/mr-speedster/CS-Buddy.git)
- ADCart: An Online Shopping Web System with TopSale, All Brand, Men, Women, Kid categorys and Add to Cart features, also an admin phase to add products to the online shop using Laravel and MySql. (https://github.com/mrspeedster/ADshop-Laravel.git)
- ADChat: A Web Chat System using PHP and MySql.(https://github.com/mr-speedster/ADChat.git)

Work Experience _____

SOTI
Associate Software Developer

Smart City, Kochi, Kerala

July 2023 - Present

• Software Developer

Bagmo Private Limited

Onsite - Kinfra Hi-Tech Park Kalamassery Ernakulam April 2023 - June 2023

PHP Laravel Developer Intern

PHP - Laravel Developer

SEPTEMBER 12, 2023

Freelancer Remote

Web Developer Mar 2020 - July 2023

- PHP Laravel
- · Nodejs Express

GeeksforGeeks Online

Article Writer

· Technical Article Writer

Skills_

Programming Python (Django, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn.), C#(.NET 6), PHP(Laravel), JavaScript(Angular, React), SQL(MySql).

Tools VScode, Git(GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket), Colab, Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook, Chrome

Miscellaneous Linux, Firebase, Kaggle.

Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation.

Achievements_

2023	Web Development Tools: Enhance Workflow and Code Qualitys, LinkedIn Learning	Online
2023	Google Analytics, Google	Online
2022	Python, Kaggle	Online
2020	Programming for Everybody, University of Michigan	Online
2020	C/C++, COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING AND MANAGEMENT, PUNNAPRA.	Kerala, India

Interests_

Technologies

I enjoy exploring and learning about new technologies and frequently switch between them

Sports

I enjoy participating in a wide range of sports and love taking part in various sports events.

Art Drawing has been a passion of mine since childhood, and I still enjoy it to this day

Games I always had the gaming gene.

Workout Working out regularly for achieving and maintaining overall fitness.

Languages_

English Professional proficiency **Malayalam** Native proficiency

September 12, 2023 2